Finding Aid for Homeopathic Medical School (University of Michigan) publications, 1874-1922
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Homeopathic Medical School (University of Michigan) publications 1874-1922
University of Michigan. Homeopathic Medical School.
1 linear foot
017 Bimu C101 2
Homeopathic Hospital at the University of Michigan, publications include Includes annual reports, bulletins, lectures such as the "Introductory Lecture of Professor E. C. Franklin Before the Homoeopathic College of the University of Michigan," a newsletter entitled the "Bulletin," reports, reprints, and schedules. Also includes the journal University Homoeopathic Observer
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Publications are received periodically from the unit (donor # #647 ). #647
The Publications are open for research
The Homeopathic Medical College was established at the University of Michigan in 1875 and continued to educate doctors, alongside the Medical School (allopathy), until 1922.
The Homoeopathic Medical School Publications contains one series, Unit Publications. The series includes announcements from 1875 through 1922, two issues of Ann Arbor Alumnus: A Quarterly Journal, and the journal University Homeopathic Observer for 1907 through 1914. Also included are several reprints, reports and lectures from the school which mainly concern the defense of homeopathic medicine in the face of its numerous detractors.
Subjects:
University of Michigan. Homoeopathic Medical School.; Homeopathy--Study and teaching--Michigan--Periodicals.
Genre Terms:
Annual reports.; Bulletins.; Journals.; Lectures.; Newsletters.; Reprints.; Schedules (time plans)
- Unit Publications
  - Addresses (Box 1)
    - Individualization (reprint from the University Homeopathic Observer ), 1909 (Box 1)
  - Announcements
    - Homeopathic Medical College, 1875-1908, 5 folders (Box 1)
    - Homeopathic Department, 1908-1911, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Homeopathic Medical College, 1911-1915, 3 folders (Box 1)
    - Homeopathic Medical School, 1915-1922, 3 folders (Box 1)
    - Practitioners’ Course, 1906 (Box 1)
  - Annual Reports
    - Homeopathic Hospital Annual Report, 1909-1918, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Journals
    - Ann Arbor Alumnus: A Quarterly Journal, 1890 (Box 1)
    - University Homeopathic Observer, 1907-1914, 4 folders (Box 1)
  - Lectures
    - The Grounds of a Homeopath’s Faith: Three lectures delivered at the request of matriculates of the Department of Medicine and Surgery (old school) of the University of Michigan, by Samuel A. Jones, 1880 (Box 1)
    - Introductory Lecture of Professor E.C. Franklin, Before the Homeopathic College of the University of Michigan, 1878 (Box 1)
    - Six Lectures Upon the Different Phases of Tuberculosis Delivered at the University of Michigan, 1906 (Box 1)
  - Newsletters
    - Bulletin, 1897 (Box 1)
  - Reports
    - Homeopathy in the University of Michigan--Resolutions of the Graduates--Action of the Alumni, 1876 (Box 1)
    - Is There But One School of Medicine? The Homeopathic Standpoint, 1921 (Box 1)
    - What I Saw in Ann Arbor, by S.R. Beckwith, [1880] (Box 1)
  - Reprints
    - Homeopathy in Michigan University--Further review of statements made by the medical faculty and president, 1875 (Box 1)
    - The New Homeopathic Hospital at the University of Michigan, by R.S. Copeland, 1900 (Box 1)
    - Review of Prof. Palmer’s statement respecting the relations of himself and colleagues to homeopathy in the University, 1875 (Box 1)
  - Schedules
    - Schedule of Lectures, 1900/01 (Box 1)